This is the air of a battlefield, huh?
（貂(てん)）戦う前から これかよ…
のまれるものか！
Like hell I'm going to let this swallow me!
The Feixin Unit headquarters got behind us before I had laid out my encircling net
（氷鬼(ひょうき)）俺が包囲網を敷く前に
飛信(ひしん)隊本陣は裏へ抜けていた
and they joined up with their scattered soldiers.
そして
散開していた兵とも合流していた
This rapid reorganization...
この迅速な立て直し…
明らかに 何者かが
参謀として隊に加入している
It is clear that someone has joined their unit as a staff officer!
I will measure what level of strategist it is with this move!
どの程度の軍師か
この一手で測らせてもらう
Here they come!
（田孝(でんこう)）来た 敵先鋒隊(せんぽうたい)！
The enemy vanguard!
They've suddenly moved 1,000 of their 4,000 soldiers.
全軍4,000のうちの1,000を
いきなり動かしてきた
And this is an elite unit!
しかも あれは精鋭部隊か！
戦を急いでいるということじゃない
They're not trying to hurry the battle.
（田孝）河了貂(かりょうてん)！
迎撃しないと 敵が どんどん…
He Liao Diao, unless we meet them, the enemy will keep getting closer...
いいんだ！
（田孝）えっ？
It's all right!
（貂）向こうからは見えていない
They can't see from over there,
but there are a lot of forked paths in the State of Wei's way!
魏国(ぎこく)軍の行く手には
いくつもの岐路があることを！
Outwit
オオッ！ 敵が分散したぞ
（貂）よし！
Oh, the enemy has split up!
Okay!
Not only are their numbers divided, but the path gets even narrower so that their impact point is smaller.
兵力が分散したうえに
その先は狭いから 衝突面が小さい
（貂）だから―
So...
500 will be more than enough to defeat their force of 1,000!
1,000に対し500の兵力で
十分 打ち勝つことができるんだ
First, using a heavyweight unit we dam up one road tight.
まずは重量級の部隊で
ひとつの道をガッチリ せき止める
（槍兵(やりへい)たち）トリャー！
（貂）そこから更に 力ずくで前進
敵を分岐点まで押し戻す
After that, we'll push forward with all our might
and bring the enemy back to the fork.
If we do that, the entrances to individual smaller paths will be closed off.
そうすれば それぞれの小道は
入り口に蓋をされた状態になる
（魏兵Ａ）う… 後ろで異変が！
（道清(どうせい)）なに？
There's something strange going on behind us!
What?!
（魏兵）後方に敵が！
（魏兵）バカな！
Enemies from behind?! How?!
With their path of retreat suddenly cut off, the enemy units are sure to fall into confusion.
突然 退路を断たれた敵の各隊は
必ず混乱に陥る
（竜有(りゅうゆう)たち）ヤーッ！
（尾平(びへい)たち）ウオーッ！
And we'll use that opportunity to mow them down!
（貂）その機に乗じて
一気に たたくんだ！
（魏兵）ウワッ！
（兵士）ハハッ… 弱(よえ)え！
弱えッスよ こいつら！
Man, these guys are freakin' weak!
They're panicking because they don't have any idea what's going on!
（竜有）状況がつかめず
混乱してるからだ！
These guys... they're like how we were just a little while ago!
（尾平）ヤツら まるで
ついさっきまでの俺たちみてえだ
クッ… うろたえるな！
退路など 初めから必要ない！
Do not lose your heads!
We never needed a path of retreat to begin with!
（魏兵Ａ）千人将！
Thousand-Man General!
（道清）
各隊 前の敵だけに集中しろ！
All units, focus only on the enemy up ahead!
The enemies numbers are nothing significant!
敵は 大した兵力ではない！
First, form files!
（道清）まずは隊列を整えろ！
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
（田孝）
クッ… マズイ！ 早くも立て直しを
Oh no! They're regrouping already!
（貂）
いや 隊長の居場所が分かった
No, now we know where the captain is!
そいつを討てば
その隊は終わりだ！
If you take him down, they're finished!
（田有(でんゆう)）ンンッ！
Lord Dao Qing!
（魏兵たち）道清さま！
（飛信隊兵たち）田有百人将！
Tian You Hundred-Man General!
If I clash with you head on, you're not a match for me!
まともに かち合えりゃ
お前らなんて 相手じゃねえんだよ
E-Emergency Report!
（伝令）きゅ… 急報！
道清千人将 討ち死に！
Thousand-Man General Dao Qing has been killed!
隊も ほぼ壊滅しました！
His unit is now almost wiped out as well!
（魏兵）な… なんだと！
（魏兵）こんな短時間で…
W-What?!
In such a short amount of time?!
（間永(かんえい)）氷鬼…
Bing Gui.
（氷鬼）甘く見過ぎたか…
I suppose I underestimated them.
Entire vanguard, charge!
前衛全体 突撃だ！
（魏兵たち）はっ！
Yes, sir!
か… 河了貂 敵が！
H-He Liao Diao, the enemy...
広がりながら前進してきたぞ！
They're advancing while still spread out!
Bing Gui, if they enter those paths...
（間永）氷鬼…
あの道に入っていっては
同じ目に遭うのではないのか？
won't they just meet the same fate as the others?
No need to worry.
ご心配なく
先ほどの敵の戦術は―
The enemy's current strategy will only be effective if our army is focused on a narrow path.
あくまで 我が軍が隘路(あいろ)に
集中した場合に効果を得る代物
If our units fragment and take every path
部隊を細分化して
あらゆる道から進ませれば―
then a small number of enemies will not be able to stop them all.
少数のヤツらに
全ては止められませぬ
And if we make it through, then we will reach the heart of the enemy.
抜ければ
部隊は一気に敵の心臓部へ届きます
攻略が早い…
やっぱり手ごわいぞ この敵
They're attacking quickly!
This really is a strong enemy!
（田孝）ああっ！
無人の道に どんどん敵が！
Enemies are entering un-manned paths one after another!
He Liao Diao!
河了貂！
（貂）隘路の戦は終わりだ
（田孝）も… もう？
The narrow path battles are over!
A-Already?!
Have the spread out units gather towards Xin on the right!
（貂）張ってる各隊を
右の信(しん)のもとに集めろ！
The right?! Not on the defense of us, the headquarters?!
（田孝）
右に？ ここの守備じゃないのか？
ここの守りに
力を割く余裕なんてない！
We can't afford to divide our power in order to protect us!
I intended to leave this place exposed from the beginning.
初めから
ここは野ざらしにするつもりだった
ええっ？ そ… そんな…
W-What?!
By exposing us, I'll draw the enemy this way.
あえて さらして 敵を引き付ける
With the Feixin Unit being injured as well as short on numbers, it can't be a drawn out fight.
数が少ないうえに
既に傷ついてる飛信隊が勝つには
長期戦ではなく―
We can only win with an incredibly short battle!
極端な短期戦！
Let's go, you bastards!
いくぞ てめえらー！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Before our headquarters falls, you've got to take out the enemy headquarters... and win!
こっちの本陣が落ちる前に
敵本陣を落として 勝つ！
Enemies incoming from the left!
（魏兵）左方より
敵が こっちに向かってきます！
（間永）う～ん… ここ狙いか
Targeting the headquarters, are they?
Fools.
バカが…
Go, go!
（田孝）いけ！ いけー！
（蒙毅(もうき)）河了貂…
He Liao Diao.
There are primarily two ways of breaking through an enemy headquarters with a massive defense.
（蒙毅）分厚く守る敵本陣を
破る手段は 主に２つある
But for the most part, the method used in actual battle
（蒙毅）しかし
実戦で使われる手段のほとんどは
is relying on power and forcing one's way through.
結局のところ
武の力に頼った強行突破だ
Of course, large sacrifices accompany using that strategy.
もちろん
その手は大きな犠牲を伴う
（信）ドリャー！
But it is because of that sacrifice that it brings about such a tremendous result.
（蒙毅）でも だからこそ
絶大な効果を生みだすんだ
（竜有）隊長に続け！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Follow the captain!
The left is now in combat!
（魏兵）左 戦闘に入りました！
押し込まれています！
They're being pushed back!
Do not panic!
（氷鬼）うろたえるな！
Send reinforcements to thicken the defense!
増援を送り 厚みを作れ！
（魏兵）ははっ！
Yes, sir!
フッ… なんだ
結局 最後は策なく いつもの力業か
Well now. It looks like in the end, they went with their usual not-thought-out brute force attack, eh?
Seems they didn't have much of a strategist after all.
ハハッ…
大した軍師ではなかったな
No, forcing their way through is a fine strategy.
いえ 強行突破は立派な策です
実戦では 敵も知恵を絞るゆえ―
Because in actual battles the enemy always thinks very carefully as well,
実際のところ 奇策だけで
勝利することは ほぼ ありません
there are few battles that can be won on clever schemes alone.
And one strategy you can be almost sure to find in the endgame is forcing one's way through.
最終的な一手は
必ずといっていいほど強行突破です
（氷鬼）要は
その一手を どこで使うかですが…
But as for how that fundamental move is being used,
with the enemy strategist having targeted it for the moment just after we sent our attack,
こちらが
攻めに出た直後をねらった敵軍師は
one could say they made the best possible choice.
最良の選択をしたと言えます
Hey now, Bing Gui, you're praising them an awful lot.
（間永）余裕だな 氷鬼
やけに褒める
褒めてはおりませぬ
ただ バカではなかったと
I am not praising them, I am merely stating that they are not idiots.
A four-layer defensive fomration!
（魏兵Ａ）４重防陣だ！
Take your positions!
（魏兵Ｂ）配置に就け！
正面を止めて 横から そぐぞ！
Stop the front and chip away at their sides!
飛信隊の力を考慮すれば―
Considering the Feixin Unit's strength,
the previous State of Wei armies would have been defeated by this charge.
今までの魏国軍は
この突破で破れていたでしょう
But currently in this headquarters
しかし今 本陣にいるのは
訓練し尽くされた将軍と私の正規兵
are heavily-trained generals and my regular soldiers.
And on top of that, as we have witnessed the Feixin Unit's destructive power at Shanyang,
その上 山陽(さんよう)で飛信隊の破壊力を
目の当たりにした我らが―
we are certain not to misread how to cope with it!
その対応を見誤ることは
絶対にない！
（田永(でんえい)）ハッ…
（氷鬼）故に 飛信隊の勝利は
万にひとつも ありえない
Therefore, the Feixin Unit does not have the slimmest chance of victory!
Lord Xin, enemy reinforcements are flooding in!
（渕(えん)）信どの 敵の増援が一気に！
These guys are pretty damn good at fortifying their fronts!
（飛信隊Ａ）こいつら
前の固め方がハンパねえ！
Th-The enemy is reacting abnormally fast!
（田孝）
て… 敵の対応が異常に早い！
Th-The captain and the others are being swallowed!
た… 隊長たちが のまれていく！
Th-The enemy's at our feet!
て… 敵が足元に！
He Liao Diao, we must seek shelter!
河了貂 早く退避を！
（貂）放っとけ！
Ignore them!
放っとけったって…
What, ignore them?
Stones or whatever you can get your hands on, throw something down there!
石でも何でもいい 下へ投げろ！
（兵士たち） お… おお！
R-Right!
（田孝）か… 河了貂！
H-He Liao Diao, do we give the signal now?!
合図は まだか！
（貂）まだだ！
Not yet!
Hang in there, everyone... Xin...
頑張ってくれ みんな…
信！
（斬る音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
Dammit, what kinda strategy is this, brat?!
（沛浪(はいろう)）クッ！ こんな作戦…
ざけんなよ あのガキ！
You must still be okay if you're able to fling insults!
（崇原(すうげん)）悪態がつけるなら
まだ大丈夫だな！
うるせえ！
Sheddep!
（間永）
まだ つぶれぬか… しぶといな
Have they still not fallen? How stubborn.
Shall we settle this?
（氷鬼）もう決めましょう
Further reinforcements!
更に増援だ！
後ろも囲い
絶対に隊長 信を取り逃がすな！
Surround them from behind as well!
We must not let the captain, Xin, escape!
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
（魏兵）飛信隊 信を殺せ！
Kill Feixin Unit Xin!
Enemy reinforcements are coming!
敵の増援が来る！
さっきより多いぞ！
This is even more than before!
Good.
よっし…
Now's the time, bastards!
こっからだ 野郎ども！
飛信隊の底力 見せつけてやれ！
Let's show them the real strength of the Feixin Unit!
Goddammit!
こんちきしょう！
He Liao Diao, hurry! The enemy!
（田孝）河了貂 早く！ 敵が！
The enemy's defenses are shifting completely towards Xin now!
（貂）
敵の守備が完全に信のほうへ偏った
今だ！ 合図の旗！
Now! The signal flag!
（地響き）
何だ？ この音は
What's that sound?
Behind me?!
後ろ？
And the second way of taking down an enemy headquarters,
（蒙毅）敵本陣を討つ２つ目の手段
それは
巧みな仕掛けで敵の守備に穴を開け
that is to use a clever trick to open a hole in the enemy's defenses
and launch one all-out surprise attack on them!
一撃必殺の奇襲攻撃を加える戦術だ
The Feixin Unit's Guo Bei soldiers have been sighted!
（烈(れつ)弟）飛信隊郭備(かくび)兵 見参！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（魏兵）て… 敵襲！ 敵襲です！
（間永･氷鬼）アア…
A-An enemy attack! Enemy attack!
（斬る音）
…たく 貂のヤツ 大したもんだぜ！
Man, that Diao really knows what she's doing!
I never guessed she'd use me as a decoy!
まさか
この俺を囮(おとり)に使うなんてよ！
Xin
So ya caught the enemy general, eh?
敵将を捕らえたのか！
（烈弟）ハハハッ… やりました！
We did it!
（田永）
なんで ぶっ殺してねえんだ？
Why don't you kill us?!
（烈弟）娘軍師に
“できれば生け捕りにしろ”と
The strategist girl told us to take you alive if possible.
（田永）生け捕り？
Alive?
（烈弟）
なんでも“平定の戦いだから”とか
She said because it's a suppression battle, or something.
まあ 本営に渡しゃ
手柄になるから いいだろう
If we hand them over to the army headquarters, it'll be a real achievement, so I'm okay with it.
Hey, look!
お… おい あれ！
The headquarters!
本陣が…
俺たちの本陣が焼け落ちてる！
Our headquarters is being burned down!
Huh?! What's going on?!
（沛浪）なに？ どうなってんだ？
Did our side get taken down at the same time?!
同時に
あっちも落とされたってことか？
Well, we did use so many soldiers to attack that there were barely any left defending for the headquarters.
（松左(しょうさ)）
確かに 攻めに兵を使ったんで―
本陣の守備は
ほとんど いなかったはず…
W-What?!
な… なんだって！
Don't tell me that brat decided to sacrifice herself?!
まさか
あのガキ 自分を犠牲にして…
Hey, don't write me off that easily!
こら！ 勝手に殺すな
（信）貂！
（田永）ガキ！
Diao!
Brat!
お前 あの本陣は…
What about the headquarters?
ああ 負けた腹いせに
ヤツらが火でも つけたんだろう
Looks like they lit a fire in retaliation to their defeat.
あと 俺がいなかったから
That, and because I was gone.
That was quite something, escaping an enemy encirclement with so few soldiers.
（渕）しかし よく
その兵の少なさで敵の包囲を…
Well, I at least made sure to have a secure escape route from the beginning.
（貂）脱出経路くらい確保しとくよ
最初っからね
（尾平）アハハッ… すっげえ！
Awesome!
何なんだ？ こいつは
大したタマだぜ まったく！
Man, what's with this girl? She's really something!
Bing Gui?
うん？ 氷鬼？
こんな小娘が―
A little girl like this really is what allowed us to win!
マジで俺たちを勝たせやがった
（貂）ああ？
（沛浪）
こりゃ まいったぜ　なっ？ 田永
Man, I'm beat.
Right, Tian Yong?!
Guess it looks that way.
（田永）ケッ！ たまたまだろう
（沛浪）ハハッ… 素直じゃねえな
Ain't you honest?!
（氷鬼）クッ… ふざけるな！
（信･貂）うん？
Quit screwing around!
こ… こんな小娘だっただと？
Y-You're saying it was this girl?!
I, Bing Gui, a man counted as one of the 8 best in the State of Wei, lost to this little girl?!
こんな小娘に―
魏国で８本の指に入るといわれた
この氷鬼が負けただと？
I will not accept it!
俺は認めんぞ
This surprise attack would seem absurd when looked at on a table...
こんな奇襲は机上の絵空事
下策中の下策だ！
The poorest of poor plans!
たまたま 飛信隊が高い戦闘力を
持っていたから成功したが
It may have succeeded merely because the Feixin Unit happened to have quite high attack power,
but with a normal unit, the decoy would've been wiped out and the surprise attack would've also ended in failure!
普通の隊なら 囮は全滅し
奇襲も失敗に終わる
And I'm sure there was major damage as well!
実際 大きな被害も出たはずだ
Hey,
（信）おい！
quit yammering, old man.
ウダウダうるせえぞ おっさん
（氷鬼）“おっさん”？
Old man?!
（信）だったら こいつの策は―
If that's the case, then her plan was really awesome because it used the Feixin Unit's strengths to its fullest potential, right?
飛信隊の力を最大限に生かした
すげえもんだってことじゃねえか
You lost to her in a battle of wits.
お前は
知恵比べで こいつに負けたんだよ
飛信隊軍師 河了貂にな！
（貂）ハッ…
The Feixun Unit strategist, He Liao Diao!
Make sure you get that name into your skull!
この名前
よ～く頭に たたき込んどけ！
Xin...
（貂）信…
Take them with us.
（信）連れてけ
Hell yeah! We won!
しゃ！ 勝ったぞ！
よう！
（貂）信…
Hey.
Xin...
What're ya doing?
何やってんだ？ お前
We've got a reason to be excited for the first time in a while.
せっかく久々に
ゆっくり盛り上がってんだ
C'mon.
来いよ
I'm fine.
（貂）俺は いいよ
I've got to come up with a plan for the terrain we're heading to next.
次に行く場所の地形に合った作戦を
考えないといけないから
You can do that stuff tomorrow, can't ya?
（信）
…んなもん あしたでいいだろう
そうはいかない！
（信）うん？
No, I can't!
If I make just a little mistake,
俺が少しでも間違えれば
数十人単位で人が死んでしまうんだ
dozens of people could die.
策を練り上げておかなくちゃ
I've got to refine my plans.
You don't need to burden yourself with the number of dead.
（信）死人の数まで お前は
しょい込まなくていいんだよ
Like hell I can't!
…んなわけにいくかよ！
しょい込むに決まってんだろう
Of course I need to bear that burden!
戦場で指示するとき―
When I give instructions on the battlefield
I calculate about how many will die when I send them in!
俺は どのくらい死ぬかも
計算に入れて 送り出してんだぞ
Diao...
貂…
A strategist has to have hostility.
（貂）軍師には適性ってのがあって
初陣で
一応 それは示せたと思ってる
And I think I displayed that at least in that first campaign.
でも 先のことを考えると
どうしても怖くなる
But when I think about what happened, I can't help but feel scared.
Close to 100 of our men died in that battle.
今回の戦で100人近くが死んだ
“この先 何百人
死なせていくんだろう”って…
And now I'm thinking how many hundreds I'm going to let die after this...
俺のこと 自分の娘に似てるって
言ってくれたヤツも―
There was even a guy that said I reminded him of his daughter...
that died in my plan.
俺の作戦で死んだ
わざわざ励ましに来てくれたのに
俺は そいつを…
He went out of his way to cheer me up, and I...
I can't get that smile back now...
もう取り戻せないんだ
あの笑顔は…
You should go home after all.
やっぱ帰れ お前
（貂）なっ…
（信）戦に出りゃ 誰かを殺す
When you go to war, you'll kill somebody.
Whether it's an ally or an enemy, you can't measure just how much blood and tears are flowing...
味方だろうが 敵だろうが―
その裏で流れる血と涙は
計り知れねえ
That's why we take that as part of winning and move forward.
そして 勝った者(もん)は
それを全部 背負って前に行く
That's why the weight on our backs gets a lot heavier when we win.
だから…
勝つ度に
背中は とんでもなく重くなる
そういう苦しみがあることも
知らずに来たんなら とっとと帰れ
If you came here without knowing about that sorta pain,
then you should get out of here now.
（貂）だ… 誰が帰るか！
Who said anything about leaving?!
俺は ただ 分かってたけど
I'm just saying that I knew that, but it's a lot heavier than I imagined!
実際 やっぱり想像以上に重いって
話をしただけだろう
それに そんな軽い気持ちで
ここに来たんじゃない！
I didn't take coming here that lightly!
Yeah, you didn't!
ヘヘッ… だよな！
えっ？
（信）だから 戦場の大先輩が―
So as someone who's far your senior as far as the battlefield goes,
ここで続けてくコツを
教えてやろうっつってんだ
I'll show you the ropes for what you're gonna be up against!
So gimme your hand!
手ぇ貸してみろ
手？
Hand?
See, this is how it goes!
（信）おら！ こうすんだ！
Hey, Xin!
（貂）
お… おい 信！ ちょ… 痛い！
That hurts!
Never mind, c'mon!
いいから来い！
（貂）アア…
仲間の死のつらさは
軍師も兵士も変わんねえ
The pain of losing comrades is no different for a strategist as it is for a soldier.
But we know the best way...
だが そのつらさを
乗り越える いちばんいい方法を
俺たちは知ってる
of overcoming that pain.
We share it together, dilute it, then we fool around and blow it all away.
（信）みんなで共有して 薄めて
バカ騒ぎして 吹っ飛ばすのさ
お前も やれ！
もう飛信隊なんだからよ
Why don't you join in?
You're part of the Feixin Unit now!
Yes! You write it like this, like this, like this!
（笑い声）
（兵士）ヒ～ッ！ 死ぬ！
Go to hell!
The Guo Bei soldiers are the best!
（兵士）郭備兵 最高！
あれを 俺にやれと？
You want me to do that?
（兵士）オッ！ 娘軍師 来た！
It's the strategist girl!
（兵士）ギャーッ！ 見んといて！
（兵士）ハハッ… 来た来た！
Ah, look!
She's here!
こっち おいで 貂ちゃ～ん！
C'mere, Miss Diao!
I won't accept it!
（田永）俺は認めねえぞ
（崇原）うるせえぞ 田永！
Shup up, Tian Yong!
Xin...
信…
（信）うん？
な… 何だよ？
Wh-What is it?
Let go of my hand already, it's embarrassing.
もう手ぇ離せよ　恥ずかしい
（信）なっ…
Wha?!
てめえ この野郎！
俺だって 別に…
You bastard! I wasn't...
Yeah, I know!
分かってるよ！
Okay, let's go!
おし！ 行こうぜ！
おらぁ！
Here comes Xin!
（兵士）信が来た！
（兵士）お前(めえ)は来んな！
You, stay outta here!
（信）…んだと こら！
（兵士）ウワッ！
What was that, asshole?!
Whadda ya mean stay outta here?!
Thank you, Xin...
（貂）ありがとうな 信
あっ… お～い！
Hey!
Vice Captain Chu Shui and the others are back!
楚水(そすい)副長たちの帰還だ！
We brought Vice Captain Chu Shui.
（田孝）楚水副長をお連れしました
（貂）うん
Right.
With the headquarters moving on our own all over the place, getting supplies must've been pretty hard.
本陣が自分勝手に動き回るから
補給作業はホントに大変だったね
これからは そういう仕事なんかも
俺が受け持つから
I'll take on that sorta work from now on,
so you can rest easy and go back to the front lines.
安心して
前線に復帰してもらっていいよ
Who is this girl?
（楚水）誰ですか？ この小娘は
えっ？
教えたって言ってませんでしたか？
Didn't you say you told him?!
Are you Lord Xin's little sister?
信どのの妹か？
（貂･田孝）いやいやいや！
No, no, no!
（田孝）彼女は河了貂といいまして
我々の新しい軍師…
Her name is He Liao Diao and she's our new strategist.
…っし！ やっと形が整ったな
All right. We're finally back in full form.
Yeah, yeah. Nice to meet you.
This girl...?
From here, the Feixin Unit continued its steady momentum.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）ここから
飛信隊は破竹の快進撃を続けた
うらぁ！
With the State of Wei focusing on Lijing as an opening to take back Shanyang,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
山陽奪還の突破口として―
里井(りせい)の地に集結してきた魏国軍を
逆に一網打尽にし
it instead turned out to be a big roundup of their forces.
僅か10日ほどで
里井を平定したのである
And in a mere 10 days Lijing was subjugated.
The Feixin Unit is coming out here?
（陸仙(りくせん)）飛信隊が こんな所まで…
Yes. With no more enemies to defeat in Lijing,
（蒙恬(もうてん)）ああ
里井に討つ敵がいなくなったから
they're heading north.
Shanyang
Weizi
Lijing
北上してきたんだ
楽華(がくか)隊と連携して
微子(びし)の魏国軍を討とうって
A messenger told me they are joining up with the Yuehua Unit to take down the State of Wei army in Weizi.
伝者が来たよ
どうやら ヤツら
以前の力を取り戻したようですね
Well, it seems they've gotten the strength that they had before back.
It's even more than before.
前以上さ
（陸仙）えっ？
In the battles where they captured Lijing,
里井の攻略戦…
飛信隊は対峙(たいじ)した敵だけでなく―
it wasn't just the enemies the Feixin Unit confronted that they beat.
里井の一帯にいた魏国軍全てを
相手にしたような戦いを展開した
That battle developed into them fighting all of the State of Wei armies in the area.
At times, they made use of ally State of Qin Army positions and assistance
時には 味方の秦国(しんこく)軍の配置や
支援を利用して
and saw all of Lijing as one large battlefield on which they were victorious.
里井全体を１つの戦場と見立てて
それに勝利した
In other words, they succeeded in a "wide scale battle".
つまり 広域戦をやってのけたんだ
The Feixin Unit has clearly gained a power they did not have up till now.
飛信隊は明らかに 今まで
持っていなかった力を手に入れた
And with the Feixin Unit currently being an independent reserve unit
独立遊軍としての形が
できつつある今の飛信隊は―
本当に強いぞ
they are truly strong.
Preview
Distant Thunder
End